



Phuong-Duy Nguyen

• Work: No. 9, Hai Thuong Lan Ong St., 94000, Can Tho, Vietnam

Email: nguyenpd1996@gmail.com **\ Phone:** (+84) 966048346

Website: https://nguyenphd.github.io/

Website: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=vejplgsAAAAJ&hl=vi

Website: https://orcid.org/0000-0002-6352-7980

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/phuongduy-nguyen/

Date of birth: 11 Nov 1996 Nationality: Vietnamese

ABOUT ME

I am currently working as a researcher at Can Tho Institute (Vietnam), and a local consultant for development projects in the Vietnamese Mekong Delta. I have experience conducting in-depth studies, needs assessments, (pre)feasibility studies, field surveys for both public sector-led and international projects.

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

[14 Sep 2014 – 19 Jan 2018] Bachelor of Natural Resource Economics

Can Tho University https://www.ctu.edu.vn/

Address: Campus 2, 3/2 St., Xuan Khanh, Ninh Kieu, 940000, Can Tho, Vietnam | Field(s) of study: Social sciences, journalism and information: • Economics | Final grade: 3.06 **Level in EQF:** EQF level 6 | **Type of credits:** Vietnamese credits Number of **credits:** 140 | **Thesis:** Valuing health risks related to the use of pesticides in agricultural production in Vinh Long province (Vietnam) using choice experiment method

[17 Apr 2024 – 25 Apr 2024]

Short training on 'Regional development and economic activation'

International Urban Training Center (Korea) and UN-Habitat iutc.gwd.go.kr/user/main.do

City: Gangwon-do | Country: South Korea | Field(s) of study: Social sciences, iournalism and information: • Economics

- Urban and city development;
- · Regional development and regeneration;
- Principles on local resource utilization for development;
- Social welfare policies and practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[1 Nov 2022 – Current] Research Associate

Can Tho Institute for Socio-Economic Development Studies http://cids.org.vn/

Address: No. 9, Hai Thuong Lan Ong St., Vien KT-XH TP. Can Tho, 94000, Can Tho, Vietnam **Email address:** vkt@cantho.gov.vn | **Name of unit or department:** Department of Scientific Research | **Business or sector:** Professional, scientific and technical activities

- · Conducted desk and field research on Environmental and Urban Studies, Public Policy, Environmental Economics, reporting to Institute and city leadership;
- · Proposed research ideas on revelant topics; and,
- Prepared materials for submission to granting agencies and scientific journals;

[1]an 2022 - Current] Consultant

Independent consultant services

City: Can Tho | Country: Vietnam | Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

Provide consulting services on techniques, methods, needs assessments and procedures for implementing projects in localities (Mekong region, Vietnam).

[1 May 2021 – 31 Dec 2021]

Project Associate

Vietnam Chammer of Commerce and Industry (VCCI) - Branch in Mekong Delta https://www.vccimekong.com.vn/vi

Address: No. 12, Hoa Binh St., Ninh Kieu, VCCI Building, 94000, Can Tho, Vietnam | Emai l address: thuonglinhct@gmail.com | Name of unit or department: Department of International Relation and Entrepreneur | **Business or sector:** Professional, scientific and technical activities

- Worked towards building the resilience and disaster management practices for businesses of the Vietnamese Mekong Delta;
- Developed and operated the Mekong Delta Resilient Business Network (MRBN);
- Did research into climate change's impacts on private sectors in the Vietnamese Mekong Delta, with concentration on saline intrusion and drought;
- Implemented communication activities for the MRBN network;
- Prepared training materials on business continuity and resilience practices.

[1 Feb 2018 – 30 Apr 2021] University Research Assistant

School of Economics, Can Tho University https://cse.ctu.edu.vn/en/departmentofenviromental-and-resource-economics.html

Address: Campus II, 3/2 St., Truong Kinh Te, 94000, Can Tho, Vietnam | Email address: t <u>ydan@ctu.edu.vn</u> | **Name of unit or department:** Department of Environmental and Resource Economics | **Business or sector:** Professional, scientific and technical activities

- Conducted and assisted in studies of agricultural, food and environmental economics.
- Managed and handled relevant administrative affairs.
- Designed questionnaires/experiments for relevant studies.
- Collected, processed, analyzed, and managed research data for relevant projects.
- Proposed research ideas; and prepared materials for submission to granting agencies.
- Written technical reports, and manuscripts for submission to scientific journals.

PUBLICATIONS

[2024] Vietnam's Online Platform Workers

Reference: La Trobe Asia Brief - La Trobe University

Tong YD, Pham LDH, M-Tradenta J, Nguyen PD & Nguyen NY (2024). Vietnam's Online Platform Workers. Policy Brief - La Trobe Asia, La Trobe University, Issue No. 11.

Insights into PCI and DDCI as Key Metrics for Measuring Subnational [2024] **Competitiveness in Vietnam**

Reference: Institutiones Administrationis – Journal of Administrative Sciences

Nguyen PD, Dinh TP, Pham TBN (2024). Insights into PCI and DDCI as Key Metrics for Measuring Subnational Competitiveness in Vietnam. Institutiones Administrationis – Journal of Administrative Sciences, 4(1), 115-128. DOI:10.54201/iajas.v4i1.102

Potential for GHG emissions savings from replacing short motorcycle trips with

[2023] active travel modes in Vietnam

Reference: Transportation (Spinger)

2/6

Tong YD, Maraseni T, **Nguyen PD**, An-Vo DA, M-Tradenta J, Tran TAD (2023). Potential for GHG emissions savings from replacing short motorcycle trips with active travel modes in Vietnam. Transportation. DOI:10.1007/s11116-023-10394-0

Gender Wage Disparity in Vietnam - the Role of Education and Labour Market [2021] Diversification

Reference: Proceedings of the 1st International Scientific Conference of Global Vietnamese Young Scientists

Nguyen DD, **Nguyen PD** and Nguyen HT (2021). Gender Wage Disparity in Vietnam – the Role of Education and Labour Market Diversification. Proceedings of the 1st International Scientific Conference of Global Vietnamese Young Scientists 2021, SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=4517278 or https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4517278

Consumer responses towards non-GM food: Evidence from experimental auctions in Vietnam

Reference: International Journal of Food and Agricultural Economics

Tong YD, Khuu TPD, Toan TD, **Nguyen PD** and Pham N (2021). Consumer responses towards non-GM food: Evidence from experimental auctions in Vietnam. International Journal of Food and Agricultural Economics, 9(4), 207-308. DOI:10.22004/ag.econ.316274

Are consumers willing to pay more for traceability? Evidence from an auction experiment of Vietnamese pork

Reference: International Journal of Food and Agricultural Economics

Tong YD, Khuu TPD, Toan TD, **Nguyen PD** and Pham N (2021). Consumer responses towards non-GM food: Evidence from experimental auctions in Vietnam. International Journal of Food and Agricultural Economics, 9(4), 207-308. DOI:10.22004/ag.econ.316274

Evaluate the recording and keeping information according to Global GAP standards[2019] of black tiger shrimp farms (Penaeus monodon) in Ca Mau province

Reference: CTU Journal of Science

Khuu TPD, Tong YD and **Nguyen PD** (2019). Evaluate the recording and keeping information according to Global GAP standards of black tiger shrimp farms (Penaeus monodon) in Ca Mau province. CTU Journal of Science, 55(2D), 15-121. DOI:10.22144/ctu.jvn.2019.054

Valuing health risk due to pesticides use in agricultural production in Tam Binh district, Vinh Long province: A choice experiment approach

Reference: CTU Journal of Science

Nguyen PD, Tong YD and Vu TD (2018). Valuing health risk due to pesticides use in agricultural production in Tam Binh district, Vinh Long province: A choice experiment approach. CTU Journal of Science, 54(7D), 164-171. DOI:10.22144/ctu.jvn.2018.153

PROJECTS

[2024] Pre-Feasibility Study for Sustainable Urban Cooling Cities in Vietnam Cities

- Project was fully funded by Global Green Growth Institute (GGGI) Vietnam.
- Role: Environmental Economics Consultant.
- Overview: The main objective of this assignment is to develop and conduct a Pre-Feasibility Study (PreFS) for assessing the viability and potential of implementing cooling solutions in the targeted project (NUZCITP) in Can Tho city, Vietnam. The PreFS can be done through literature review, local engagement and consultation

with relevant stakeholders, and in-depth analyses on technical issues, environmental and social impacts, and financial, economic efficiency and risks.

• Deliverable: Pre-feasibility study report.

The Current Situation of Vietnamese Online Workers and Online Labor Market [2024 – 2024] Analysis Under the Impacts of OpenAl

- Project was fully funded by Australian Alumni Grants Fund (ID:AAGF-R5-00131), led by Dr. Yen Dan Tong.
- Role: Research Team Member.
- Overview: In recent job marketplace, online platforms for labor market are emerging
 as the most innovative solution for connecting job providers and job seekers. Plus,
 the advent of modern technologies and AI have created large-scale changes to job
 and skill demand. These challenges have potential to significantly disrupt the
 current structure of job market, such as changing nature of works and augmenting
 worker's productivity. To gain an in-depth understanding of this trend, this
 research project aims to conduct the online labor market analysis in Vietnam and
 the world using data extracted from online platforms.
- Deliverables: Talkshow on the Online Labour Market in Vietnam (May 25, 2024) & the La Trobe Asia Policy Brief, titled 'Vietnam's Online Platform Workers.'

[2023 – 2024] Department and District Competitiveness Index (DDCI) - Can Tho City, Vietnam

- Project was fully funded by the People's Committee of Can Tho (Vietnam).
- Role: Project Co-Leader, Main Researcher.
- Overview: The DDCI, a derivative index of Provincial Competitiveness Index (PCI), has been built and put into operation at local administrative levels. DDCI serves as a benchmark, encompassing various facets based on PCI's key principles. PCI and DDCI metrics are Vietnam's efforts in improving institutions for a more favorable business environment.
- Deliverables: Final Report on <u>Department and District Competitiveness Index (DDCI)</u> 2023 of Can Tho City, Vietnam.

Mekong Delta Pond Liner Conversion: An Integrated Plastic Waste Management [2023] Solution for Shrimp Farm in Vietnam

- Project was fully funded by DOW Chemicals & Evergreen Social Ventures.
- Role: Local Consultant.
- Overview: The Mekong Delta Pond Liner Conversion Project addresses the increasing challenge of collecting, cleaning, pre-processing, and recycling plastic waste (pond liner) from the aquaculture industry in the Mekong Delta through a targeted total value chain approach that is replicable and sustainable. The pilot stage of this project will be conducted in Soc Trang province.
- Deliverables: Report on results of local engagement and field survey.

[2022 – 2023] Mekong Delta Resilient Business Network (MRBN)

- Project was fully funded by the UPS Foundation and the Asia Foundation.
- Role: Project Associate and Main Researcher.
- Overview: Recognizing the impact of climate change on the business sector, the
 project worked with relevant parties to establish the Mekong Delta Resilient
 Business Network. Also, my team has conducted the very fisrt study on impacts of
 climate change (focusing on salinity intrusion and severe drought) on businesses in

- the Vietnamese Mekong Delta, and needs assessment of local businesses on capacity building towards climate-adapted and resilient business.
- Deliverables: Final Report on <u>Impacts of Saline Intrusion and Drought on the</u>
 <u>Vietnamese Mekong Delta's Businesses</u>, and Needs Assessment Report: Business
 Resilience & Climate Adapation.

Project on Assessing and Promoting Hygiene, Safety, and Bio-Security Practices for [2021] Wet Markets

- Project was fully funded by the Australian Alumni Grants Fund (ID:AAGF-R3-00176), led by Dr. Yen Dan Tong.
- Role: Research Assistant, in charge of drafting the proposal and conducting field survey and data collection.
- Overview: The aim of the project is to provide insights into the current situation of wet markets in southern region of Vietnam and how to enhance biosecurity and hygiene of such workplace, while maintaining its competitiveness especially in the context of pandemic outbreak.

Research on the Role of Informal Sector in Municipal Solid Waste Management [2020 – 2021] System in Vietnam

- Project was partly funded by Can Tho University Improvement Project VN14-P6, supported by ODA from The Japan International Cooperation Agency.
- Role: Research Assistant.
- Overview: Although the informal sector of waste collection has an important role in income diversification for the poor and contribution to waste recycling, this sector is still not recognised in any government official policies and is usually underestimated in Vietnam. The study builds on the information provided by 36 scrap dealers, 127 scrap buyers, and 760 households and in-depth interviews with experts in the Mekong Delta region, Vietnam.
- Deliverables: A published article on <u>Waste Management</u> (SCI-Q1, IF 8.1), titled "Under standing the role of informal sector for sustainable development of municipal solid waste management system: A case study in Vietnam."

Air Pollution: How Much Do We Pay for That Silent Killer? and Will Bus Rapid Transit [2019 – 2021] (BRT) a Viable Solution for Vietnam's Cities?

- Project was fully funded by Vietnam National Foundation for Science and Technology Development (ID:502.01-2018.312).
- Role: Research Assistant, in charge of drafting the proposal (won the fund), and providing technical assistance (primarily on data).
- Overview: This project aims to estimate socio-economic costs of air pollution's health impacts, and then to conduct a cost-benefit analysis for the pilot BRT project in Can Tho city (Vietnam), taken into account the benefit of avoiding socioeconomic costs due to air pollution (e.g. cost of illness).
- Deliverables: Articles published in <u>Sustainability</u> "Cost-Benefit Analysis and Model Preference of Public Transportation in Can Tho City, Vietnam", and <u>Journal of the</u> <u>Asia Pacific Economy</u> "Economic analysis of exposure to the elevated level of PM10 in Vietnam: a COI and WTP approach."

HONOURS AND AWARDS

[Sep 2021] Scholarship of Vietnam School of Development Awarding institution: YSD and International Centre for Interdisciplinary Science and Education

Recognized the performance and participation in the 1st Vietnam School of Development (VSOD) and the 2nd Vietnam Summer School in Development (VSSD).

[Jul 2019] Scholarship of Vietnam School of Science Awarding institution: Rencontres du

Vietnam and International Centre for Interdisciplinary Science and Education

Recognized the excellent performance and participation in the 7th <u>Vietnam School of Science</u>.

[May 2017] **Dean's List Excellent Scholarship 2016/2017 a.y. Awarding institution:** Can Tho University

Nominated as the best undergraduate students in Natural Resource Economics major, based on performance indicated by GPA and extracurricular activities in the 2016/2017 academic year.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Vietnamese

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Office Software and Google Toolkit

Google (Google Drive, Google Docs, Google Slides, Google Sheets, Google Meets, Google Trends) | Microsoft Excel | Microsoft Word | LaTeX | Microsoft Powerpoint

Design and Searching Tools

Canva | Mendeley | ResearchRabbit.Al | Google Scholar

Data Analysis and Visualization

STATA | Vensim | SPSS | EdrawMax | NLogit

Communication and Social Media

Video Conferencing (Zoom, Teams, Skype, Webex) - Advanced | Instagram | Facebook

Can Tho, Vietnam, 17 Jul 2024